A Guide to the Virginia Governor George F. Allen Transition Office Briefing Records, 1997-1998
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Virginia Governor George F. Allen Transition Office Briefing Records, 1997-1998
The Library of Virginia
35718
1.35 cu. ft. (2 boxes)
Virginia. Governor (1994-1998: Allen)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred by Georgia Root, Assistant Secretary of the Commonwealth, Richmond, Virginia, 13 February 1998.
Biographical/Historical Information
Virginia elects its governors to four-year terms without the option of a second consecutive term. At the end of each four-year term, the exiting governor by way of the Transition Office, gathers material to present to the governor-elect. The information is presented in binders and contains reports, memoranda, correspondence, budget documents, and other briefing material. The binders also provide information on specific secretariats and agencies. The Transition Office briefing records are compiled in order to prepare the governor-elect to take office.
George Felix Allen was born March 8, 1952 in Whittier, California to famed NFL football coach George H. Allen and his wife Henrietta (Lumbroso) Allen. He graduated from the University of Virginia in 1971 and the University of Virginia School of Law in 1977. Allen served in the Virginia House of Delegates from 1982-1991 and served a short term in the U.S. House of Delegates in the early 1990s. In November 1993, Allen beat Attorney General Mary Sue Terry to become Governor. Governor Allen served until January 1998 and was suceeded by Governor James S. Gilmore. Governor Allen has been married to Susan (Brown) Allen since 1986 and they have three children, Forrest, Tyler, and Brooke. The family resides in Mount Vernon, Virginia.
Scope and Content
Contains briefing records that include information on cabinet secretariats, offices, and agencies that were used to brief Governor-elect James S. Gilmore and his staff before Governor Gilmore took office in January 1998. The records include budgetary and secretarial documents, as well as memoranda and correspondence.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into one series:
Series I. Transition Office Briefing Records
Contents List
- Series I. Transition Office Briefing Records, 1997-1998., Extent: 1.35 cu. ft (2 boxes). (Box 1-2.)
  Arranged by subject heading.
  - Memoranda Concerning Transition (To/from Jay Timmons). (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Transition Inter-Office Correspondence. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Agency Budget Requests, 1998-2000, 1997. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Agency Descriptions and Appropriations, 1997. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Briefing: Budget Process, 1998-2000, 1997. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Briefing: Employment Procedures, 1997. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Executive Orders and Executive Memoranda Issued under Governor Allen, 1997. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Briefing: Secretarial Office Operations, 1997. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Briefing: Virginia Liaison Office, 1997. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Briefing: Virginia Liaison Office, 1997. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Briefing: Office of the Secretary of the Commonwealth, 1997. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Briefing: Office of the Secretary of the Commonwealth, 1997. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Briefing: Office of the Secretary of the Commonwealth, 1997. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Briefing: Secretariat of Adminstration, 1997. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Briefing: Secretariat of Administration, 1997. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Briefing: Secretariat of Administration, 1997. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Attachments: Secretariat of Administration, Volume 1 (Blue Ribbon Strike Force Report), 1997. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Attachments: Secretariat of Administration, Volume 1, 1997. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Attachments: Secretariat of Administration, Volume 2, 1997. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Attachments: Secretariat of Administration, Volume 2, 1997. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Briefing: Secretariat of Commerce and Trade. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Briefing: Secretariat of Education, 1997. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Briefing: Secretariat of Education, 1997. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Briefing: Secretariat of Finance, 1997. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Briefing: Fiscal Outlook and Budget Preview, 1997. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Briefing: Secretariat of Health and Human Resources, 1997. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Briefing: Secretariat of Health and Human Resources, 1997. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Briefing: Secretariat of Health and Human Resources, 1997. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Briefing: Secretariat of Natural Resources, 1997. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Briefing: Secretariat of Public Safety, 1997. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Briefing: Secretariat of Transportation, 1997. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Briefing: Secretariat of Transportation (Dept. of Transportation and Dept. of Motor Vehicles), 1997. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Briefing: Secretariat of Transportation (Dept. of Transportation and Dept. of Motor Vehicles), 1997. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Briefing: Secretariat of Transportation (Dept. of Transportation and Dept. of Motor Vehicles), 1997. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - List of Allen Administration Officials submitting Resumes to the Gilmore Transition Team, 1997. (Box 2, Folder 8)